<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Life on Xeeeeon Blog</title><link>https://pilchark.github.io/en/categories/life/</link><description>Recent content in Life on Xeeeeon Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pilchark.github.io/en/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to decide the consumption</title><link>https://pilchark.github.io/en/p/how-to-decide-the-consumption/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pilchark.github.io/en/p/how-to-decide-the-consumption/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="health">Health
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The foremost consumption, which we can better call an investment, I think it&amp;rsquo;s health. The health investment includes mental health and physical health.&lt;br>
I&amp;rsquo;ve got a feeling that sometimes when I go home from work, I can&amp;rsquo;t get my mind out of the working status rapidly. So all the stuff that makes us energetic every day is worth purchasing.&lt;br>
A latex pillow, a noise-canceling headset, they are all good for us to have a rest.&lt;br>
Also, if we think a yoga mat is good for us to immerse ourselves into meditation, we can purchase that.&lt;br>
By the way, we should notice that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that we&amp;rsquo;ve formed a habit when we own the tools.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="knowledge">Knowledge
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s a proverb, &amp;ldquo;Books are the windows to the world.&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s absolutely correct.&lt;br>
But nowadays, there are some other convenient ways for us to broaden our horizons and open up our minds.&lt;br>
Online courses are convenient for us to learn new subjects, i.e., Coursera and Udemy.&lt;br>
I think they&amp;rsquo;re much better than YouTube because we must concentrate on the lecture and there are homework and quizzes for us to review what we learned in the lesson. These are important for us to absorb the knowledge.&lt;br>
Besides, it&amp;rsquo;s valuable to pay for a trip to a new city or new country. We&amp;rsquo;ll always meet new person and absorb new culture in a trip, that&amp;rsquo;s also a way of learning.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="time-saving">Time-saving
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Last but not least, it&amp;rsquo;s about time-saving.&lt;br>
I remembered a thought in an article, that we pay twice for each thing we purchase.&lt;br>
Sometimes before I buy something, I spend time looking for the lowest historical price, and then spend additional attention on the news to see if the price was reduced today. Even if I bought it at a lower price in the end, I lose the time of my attention. So in my mind, it&amp;rsquo;s worth paying a little more for the time-saving.&lt;br>
There&amp;rsquo;s another similar thing: there were a lot of pirated games and software in my country when I was a child. So I got used to finding a pirated one when a new game was released. Sometimes it takes a really long time and the download speed is very slow, which also decreases my passion. At last, the origin of satisfaction comes from finding a pirated game version instead of enjoying the story in the game. That&amp;rsquo;s not good for the developers and also for me.&lt;br>
In my mind, it&amp;rsquo;s not worth spending time on things that distract from our main goal. It seems that we spend a little more money on the surface, but it improves our concentration and helps us just enjoy today&amp;rsquo;s life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>how to travel to a new city</title><link>https://pilchark.github.io/en/p/how-to-travel-to-a-new-city/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pilchark.github.io/en/p/how-to-travel-to-a-new-city/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="1-safety-first">1. Safety First
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Personal safety should always be your top priority, no matter where you travel. If you&amp;rsquo;re visiting a country where firearms are legal, research ahead to avoid dangerous areas, slums, or conflict zones.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Safety isn&amp;rsquo;t just about avoiding crime. When traveling to places with different climates from your home, be mindful of health risks like heatstroke or extreme cold. If you&amp;rsquo;re planning activities like hiking away from city centers, ensure your phone is fully charged and consider carrying a backup phone for emergencies. Having a way to contact emergency services (like 911) could be crucial.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="2-explore-off-the-beaten-path">2. Explore Off the Beaten Path
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>When people think of major world cities, they often focus on famous landmarks - London&amp;rsquo;s Big Ben, New York&amp;rsquo;s Statue of Liberty, or Paris&amp;rsquo;s Eiffel Tower. While these are impressive, they don&amp;rsquo;t tell the whole story. To truly understand a city&amp;rsquo;s lifestyle and hidden character, venture into local markets for breakfast, observe the daily routines of street cleaners, chat with small shop owners, or watch elderly residents in parks. These authentic experiences reveal the city&amp;rsquo;s true spirit in ways that tourist attractions can&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="3-focus-on-one-main-goal">3. Focus on One Main Goal
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Many office workers, with their limited vacation time, try to pack too many attractions into their itinerary. In China, these rushed tourists are jokingly called &amp;ldquo;Navy SEAL Travelers.&amp;rdquo; This approach often leads to anxiety about completing a lengthy to-do list rather than enjoying the experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead, set one primary goal for your trip and focus on achieving it. Consider everything else a bonus. This approach helps you fully appreciate your chosen experience without the stress of rushing through multiple attractions. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve accomplished your main goal, you can relax and explore other sites if time permits.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>how to deal with fragmented addiction</title><link>https://pilchark.github.io/en/p/how-to-deal-with-fragmented-addiction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pilchark.github.io/en/p/how-to-deal-with-fragmented-addiction/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-is-fragment-addiction">What is Fragment Addiction?
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>A compulsive obsession with an activity or behavior that is so overwhelming that it disrupts one&amp;rsquo;s normal routine and daily schedule.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When someone withdraws from the activity suddenly, they experience negative emotions, feelings, and even anxiety.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-fragment-addiction-develops">How fragment Addiction Develops
&lt;/h2>&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Intrinsically&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Work-related stress or feeling the need to be productive during short breaks
leads to seeking stimulation for dopamine release in the brain.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>External&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Through algorithmic recommendations of short videos that target personal interests and preferences,
along with incentives like cash-out bonuses.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-overcome">How to overcome
&lt;/h2>&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Recognition&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Accept yourself - gaming is okay, and taking time to rest is also okay.
Don&amp;rsquo;t pressure yourself to overcome the addiction immediately. Instead, analyze how much time you spend on these activities and consider if that aligns with your goals.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>Transformation&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Create daily plans. One effective method I&amp;rsquo;ve seen involves dividing the day into time blocks and tracking completed tasks.
Try new activities and embrace challenges - they can energize you.
Step out of your comfort zone, even if it&amp;rsquo;s just one small step at a time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Involution is a phenomenon</title><link>https://pilchark.github.io/en/p/involution-is-a-phenomenon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pilchark.github.io/en/p/involution-is-a-phenomenon/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="1-what-is-an-involutioninner-scroll">1. What is an involution(inner scroll)
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>While in the working circle, students in schools study hard from each other and strive to surpass the majority of people around them.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="2-why-it-was-formed">2. Why it was formed?
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The working environment is highly competitive, few job posts with a large amount of potential competitors.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="3-conception">3. Conception
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>In the current context of fierce competition in society,
enterprises are cutting costs and there are large-scale corporate layoffs.
ordinary workers can relieve anxiety and maintain stable income.
The phenomenon of doing it to survive.
Citing the nature of domestic work, he was exhausted before retirement, but he felt disappointed after retirement.
The 70-year-old retired man in Japan still worked hard.
Here, we don&amp;rsquo;t need to compare the differences between political system,
we just say that, moderate volumes are actually beneficial to the growth of individuals in society,
However, it should not exceed the limits allowed by the individual&amp;rsquo;s physical and mental health.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="4-how-to-deal-with-it">4. how to deal with it
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;lie flat&amp;rdquo;,
The essence of human beings is that they need input and labor to get satisfaction.
Maintain a state of learning, be more receptive to new things, and take the initiative in potential future environments.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About Short Video and Movie Random Thoughts</title><link>https://pilchark.github.io/en/p/short-videos-and-movies/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pilchark.github.io/en/p/short-videos-and-movies/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="short-videos-bring-an-elevated-emotional-threshold-to-the-modern-man">Short videos bring an elevated emotional threshold to the modern man
&lt;/h1>&lt;p>The rapid development of science and technology is always a double-edged sword. While enjoying the convenience it brings, we also have to be wary of the &amp;rsquo;erosion&amp;rsquo; of us. We have entered an era of short videos, and while the density of information access has been greatly increased, it seems that we have lost our awareness of the most primitive and subtle human emotions. The fast-paced changes of short videos can sway us visually, but they can&amp;rsquo;t bring us rapid emotional ups and downs. Our brains are lagging behind in emotional changes, but this is a precious asset of human beings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But the film appeared in the little girl, her body red, that is, in the concentration camps, corpses everywhere in the Jewish city brought a touch of vitality, an uncontaminated by the war vitality, but at the same time this red so dim, seemingly seemingly nothing, at any time will be engulfed, like the color of blood.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>